我们来看看几种不同类型的机器人。我们要去的第一个
Let’s have a look at a few different kinds of robots. The first one we’re going to
考虑是所谓的龙门机器人，有时也称为笛卡尔机器人。它的
consider is what’s called a Gantry robot and sometimes called a Cartesian robot. It’s
一个允许我们控制三维空间中刀尖位置的机器人，
a robot that allows us to control the position of the tool-tip in three-dimensional space,
所以我们可以控制刀尖的X，Y和Z坐标。龙门机器人得到了
so we can control the X, Y and Z coordinate of the tool-tip. The Gantry robot has got
沿着蓝色箭头指示的方向移动并且工具移动的吊杆
a boom which moves in the direction indicated by the blue arrow and the tool moves along
红色箭头所示方向的繁荣。最后，工具本身会移动
the boom in the direction shown by the red arrow. And, finally, the tool itself moves
按绿色箭头指示的方向上下。我们有三个运动轴，
up and down in the direction indicated by the green arrow. We have three motion axes,
每个都与其他正交。这种机器人被称为SCARA机器人
each orthogonal to the others. This kind of robot is known as a SCARA robot
它们广泛用于制造和包装处理应用。
and they are widely used in manufacturing and package handling applications.
以红色突出显示的机器人部分围绕此处显示的轴旋转。
The part of the robot that’s highlighted in red rotates around the axis shown here.
并且，以蓝色突出显示的机器人部分围绕该轴旋转。最后，
And, the part of the robot that’s highlighted in blue rotates around this axis. And, finally,
该工具沿绿色箭头所示的轴上下移动。一些变种
the tool moves up and down along the axis shown here by the green arrow. Some variants
SCARA机器人还可以围绕绿色虚线所示的轴旋转工具。该
of the SCARA robots also rotate the tool around the axis shown by the green dashed line. The
术语SCARA是SelectiveComplianceArticulatingRobot的首字母缩写词，为什么复杂
term SCARA is an acronym for Selective Compliance Articulating Robot and so why the complex
和折磨的缩写？但基本上，这意味着机器人是完全自由的
and tortured acronym? But essentially, what it means is that the robot is quite free to
在水平面上移动，但在垂直方向上它是非常非常僵硬的
move in the horizontal plane, but it’s very, very stiff in the vertical direction and that’s
只是它的设计和构造方式的结果。
just a consequence of the way it has been designed and constructed.
一种相对较新的机器人是并联机器人，这是一个示例
A relatively new class of robot is the parallel link robot and this is an example of one shown
这里。并联机器人的一大优势是可以定位所有电机
here. A great advantage of the parallel link robot is all of the motors can be situated
在机器人的底座上，它们通过机械连接与工具连接。所以，那里
in the base of the robot and they are connected via mechanical linkages to the tool. So, there
是多个机械连接并联将工具连接到电动机。这是
are a number of mechanical linkages in parallel connecting the tool to the motors. This is
与龙门机器人和SCARA机器人完全不同的架构。那些机器人被推荐
a very different architecture to the Gantry robot and the SCARA robot. Those robots are referred
作为串行链接机器人，因为从基础到工具提示有一系列链接。
to as serial link robots because there is a chain of links from the base to the tool-tip.
这里，链接都是并行的。这里有几个教育的例子
Here, the links are all in parallel. Here are a couple of examples of educational
机器人。左边的那个是一个爱好机器人，有四个机械关节连接
robots. The one on the left is a hobby robot that has got four mechanical joints connecting
刀尖的底座，有平行钳口或双指夹具。
the base to the tool-tip where there is a parallel jaw or a two-finger gripper.
这里展示的AldebaranNAO机器人有两条胳膊和两条腿。并且，每个武器
The Aldebaran NAO robot shown here has got two arms and two legs. And, each of the arms
并且腿本质上是一个串行链接操纵器。在武器的情况下，那里
and the legs is essentially a serial link manipulator. In the case of the arms, there
是四个关节，两个在肩部，一个在肘部，一个在手腕，控制
are four joints, two at the shoulder, one at the elbow and one at the wrist, which control
握住许多手指的手腕的位置和方向。以及那些
the position and orientation of the wrist which holds a number of fingers. And, those
手指本身内部有许多关节。
fingers themselves have got a number of joints within them.
一类很常见的机器人有六轴，即六轴串联机器人。在
A very common class of robots have got six axes, the six-axis serial link robot. On the
左边，我们可以看到一个最先进的工业机器人的例子，它有六个
left, we can see an example of a state of the art industrial robot which has got six
链接。而且，在右侧，我们可以看到一个非常不寻常的六轴机器人示例。这个
links. And, on the right, we can see a very unusual example of a six-axis robot. This
臂用于从航天飞机的有效载荷舱装载和卸载卫星和其他货物。
arm is used to load and unload satellites and other cargo from the shuttle’s payload bay.
这是机器人手臂发展历史上非常着名的机器人手臂。它是
Here is a very famous robotic arm in the history of robot arm development. It was
在斯坦福大学开发，它通常被称为斯坦福机器人
developed at Stanford University and it’s commonly known just as the Stanford Robotic
臂。它发展于1969年。那是人们第一次登上月球的那一年。
Arm. It was developed in 1969. That’s the year that people first walked on the moon.
这种机器人手臂与今天非常普遍的机器人手臂的不同之处在于它
What differentiates this robot arm from robot arms that are very common today is that it
有一个滑动关节。该机器人中的第三个关节向后和向前滑动
has got a sliding joint. The third joint in this robot slides backwards and forwards and
改变机器人工具，手腕和机器人底座之间的距离。
changes the distance between the robot’s tool, it’s wrist and the base of the robot.
第一家生产工业机器人的公司是位于康涅狄格州的Unimation公司
The first company to produce an industrial robot was Unimation Inc, a Connecticut-based
公司和他们成立于1956年，并安装了他们的第一个工业机器人
company and they were founded in 1956 and installed their first industrial robot in
几年后到一家制造工厂。这项技术真的很老了。
to a manufacturing plant a couple of years later. The technology is really quite old.
这是1983年Unimate机器人之一的一个例子。它是PUMA560机器人，
This is an example of one of those Unimate robots from 1983. It’s the PUMA 560 robot,
真正在机器人研究史上非常着名的机器人。有很多很多
quite a famous robot really in the history of robotics research. There were many, many
这些机器人积极参与制造，但也有很多
of these robots actively involved in manufacturing, but there are also a great number of them
在大学研究实验室，如学习如何破解这些机器人，以便他们可以
in university research labs such as learning how to hack these robots so that they could
将自己的控制算法添加到机器人中。所以，很多很多早期的机器人研究论文
add their own control algorithms to the robot. So, many, many early robotics research papers
都是基于这些特殊的PUMA机器人PUMA560。
are all based on these particular PUMA robots, the PUMA 560.